So let's see how to create our own high pass filter.
现在我们来讲怎么创建高通过滤器
First I'll show you how to define your own custom kernel and later
首先我要讲怎么自定义核
we'll use openCV functions to help us build commonly used filters.
接着 我们会用 OpenCV 的函数来创建常用的过滤器
Here's an image of a building.
这是一张建筑图
It's actually San Francisco City Hall.
这栋建筑其实是旧金山市政大厅
I read it in and as usual I've made an RGB copy for image processing.
我读取了图像 照常复制了 RGB 副本 以便处理
The first thing I'll do is to convert this to grayscale
首先 把这张图转换为灰度图像
using CVT color and the code RGB to gray.
用的函数是 cvtcolor 代码是 RGB2GRAY
This way a filter will be able to detect changes in image intensity.
这样一来 过滤器就能检测到图像强度的变化了
Next, I'll create a custom edge detection filter.
接着 自定义边缘检测过滤器
I want to build one that detects vertical edges and ignores horizontal edges.
我想创建过滤器来检测垂直边缘 但不检测水平边缘
I'll do this by making a three by three matrix and using values that will
因此 我要创建一个三乘三矩阵 矩阵使用的值
calculate the difference between the left and right sides of this pixel area in an image.
要能计算图像这部分像素区域左右两边的差异
I'm starting with an empty three by three kernel.
首先 创建一个三乘三的空核
I'll put negative values on the left side,
在左边放入负值
weighty in the corners,
使角落的权重
less in the edges right next to the center pixel.
小于与中心像素相邻的边缘
I'll put zeros in the center column and then positive values on the right side.
中间一栏填 0 右边则填正值
This kernel one centered on an image pixel will calculate the difference
一旦以某个图像像素作为这个核的中心 核就会开始计算
between pixels on the right side and the left thereby detecting vertical edges.
左右两边的像素差 从而检测出垂直边缘
This is actually a really common filter called the sobel filter.
这其实是种很常见的过滤器 叫做 Sobel 过滤器
The sobel filter detects abrupt intensity changes in the x and y direction separately.
Sobel 过滤器可分别检测 x 和 y 轴方向的强度突变
This one is an approximation of the gradient or change in intensity over
这个过滤器会对 x 轴方向的空间强度梯度进行估算
space in the x direction and I'll actually name it sobel X.
也就是对强度变化进行估算 我就将其命名为 sobel_x 好了
Then, to convolve this filter with the input image,
然后 将这个过滤器和输入图像进行卷积
I'll use an openCV function called Filter2D.
使用 OpenCV 的函数 filter2D
This function takes in an input image,
这个函数的参数有 输入图像、
the type of output image,
输出图像的类型
a negative one just means the output will have the same type as the input image,
-1 指的是输出与输入类型一致
and finally the kernel we just created,
以及我们刚创建的核
sobel X, and it produces a filtered image.
即 sobel_x 函数会生成滤波后的图像 filtered image
Let's display it and see what it looks like.
把图像绘制出来 看看效果
I see basically what I expected.
基本符合我的预期
All the vertical edges are highlighted and this kind of filter
所有垂直边缘都得到了高亮
helps me detect the vertical edges of the building and the structures that surround it.
这类过滤器能帮我检测建筑及其周边结构的垂直边缘
My last step which is a useful thing to learn in
最后一步 也是计算机视觉相当实用的一步
computer vision is turning this image into a binary image.
就是将图像转换为二值图像
That is, I want to turn this into
也就是说 将其转换成
a purely black and white image with the strongest edges clearly visible.
纯粹的黑白图像 强度最高的边缘就会十分显眼了
To do that I can use the openCV function threshold.
因此 使用 OpenCV 的函数 threshold
This takes in our filtered image that we want to perform the threshold on,
该函数的参数有 滤波后想施加阀值限制的图像
a low value for the pixel values to pass through
一个供像素值通过的下限
and I'll set this at a medium high level at 100.
我就设得相对高些 设为 100 吧
Then it takes in the pixel value to turn these all into which I'll set as white or 255.
还有像素值上限 我设为白色 也就是 255
And finally the type of threshold,
最后是阀值类型
a binary threshold and I'll display this image.
设为二进制阀值 将图像绘制出来
Here we can see the stronger edges clearly and if I
我们可以清楚地看到较强的边缘
lower this threshold to say 50 and run this code again,
如果将阀值降低到 50 再运行这段代码
I'll detect more edges.
我就能检测到更多边缘
In fact too many edges to really be helpful.
事实上 检测到的边缘太多了 反而不好
So let's go back to a 100 threshold.
所以还是将阀值设回 100 吧
So here I am zooming in to see the difference between
这里我放大了图像 以便观察第一张图像 也即滤波后的图像
this first filtered image and this second binary image.
和第二张图像 也即二值图像之间的区别
We can see that in addition to the edges of
我们会发现 除了建筑、
the building and windows and other structures,
窗户和其它结构的边缘外
there are a lot of other smaller detected edges.
还检测出了许多小一些的边缘
These dots on the grass for example.
比如草地上的这些点
These don't provide any extra information about the building or scenery.
这些点并不能提供任何建筑或景物的额外信息
They're really just bloody noise.
不过是噪声而已
Noise is usually represented as dots or fuzzy details.
常见的噪声有噪点和模糊的细节
By detecting edges like this
检测这类边缘时
a high pass filter can actually exaggerate noise in an image.
高通过滤器会强化图像里的这些噪声
So we have to be cautious when we apply these filters.
所以应用这类过滤器要十分小心
Often we have to take an additional step to make sure we don't enhance undesirable noise.
通常我们需要增加一步操作 才能确保噪声得不到强化
Soon we'll see that we can use a low pass filter
很快我们就要来讲低通过滤器了
to blur an image and reduce unwanted noise.
我们要用低通过滤器来对图像进行模糊处理 以便降噪
We'll often do this before applying
在像这样使用高通过滤器之前
a high pass filter like this and we'll get into the applications
我们都会先降噪
of low pass filters after you get
等你再做几个高通过滤器边缘检测的练习后
a little more practice applying high pass edge detection and filters.
我们就来学习低通过滤器